DARREN W. DUNNE

Wake Forest, NC 27587

linkedin.com/in/darrenwdunne

darrenwdunne@gmail.com

919.524.8451

dwdunne.com

AGILE SCRUM MASTER AND SERVANT-LEADER

Contributing to Bottom Line by Increasing Efficiencies

Professional with over 10 years of success leading and coaching local and globally-distributed software development teams. Expert at driving adoption of Agile project management methodologies and successfully converting software projects from Waterfall to Agile. Passionate defender of Users and Usability, specializing in front-end software development. Strong communicator and collaborator with excellent time and project management skills.

SKILLS

Project Management Backlog Grooming, Release and Sprint Planning, Story Development, Dependency

Management, Removing Impediments, Facilitating Meetings, Reviews, and Retrospectives, Coaching, Conflict Resolution; Microsoft Project, Microsoft Excel,

Rational Team Concert (RTC), Jira

Programming Languages JavaScript, Java, HTML, Python, C, C++

Technologies Experience with CSS, Sass, Bootstrap, JSON, Responsive Web Design, AJAX/REST;

Exposure to jQuery, AngularJS, Virtualization (VMWare and AWS)

Development ToolsGit, GitHub, Eclipse, Grunt, Gulp, Microsoft Visual Studio Code, Ant, Rational

Application Developer (RAD), Rational AppScan, Yeoman

Operating Systems UNIX, Linux, Red Hat RHEL, Windows, Mac OS X

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IBM, Raleigh, NC 1996 - 2016

Software Development Manager / Project Manager

2012 - 2016

IBM Cloud and Smarter Infrastructure

Oversaw 2 development scrum teams simultaneously with 18 members in 4 countries for <u>Netcool Operations Insight</u> (<u>NOI</u>), <u>Tivoli Business Service Manager (TBSM)</u> and <u>Tivoli Netcool / Impact</u> products. Recruited, trained and mentored team members from diverse backgrounds, locations and expertise.

- Reduced major releases delivery time 80% (from more than 18 months to 3 months) by converting both teams from Waterfall to Agile.
- Decreased number of customer-reported defects 30%, and dramatically improved morale, eliminating "Us vs Them" feelings that had developed by embedding QA and technical writers into Agile scrums.
- Decreased release-to-release allowable defects from 200 to less than 10 by enforcing stricter quality standards.
- Increased customer satisfaction by converting to open development model. Delivered several Beta iterations each release and allowed customers to create, review and vote on new features.
- Achieved 100% coverage of verification of Internationalization (i18n) and Accessibility (a11y) during Scrum sprints, which had previously been performed late in release cycle by external teams.
- Eliminated long-standing "Not Invented Here" sentiments in development and management by leading integration of Open Source software.

DARREN W. DUNNE

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Senior Software Engineer / Scrum Master

2006 - 2012

IBM Tivoli

Led 16 programmers in design, development and release of 4 major multi-year releases of IBM Netcool/Impact and IBM Tivoli Business Service Manager (TBSM), delivering all releases on schedule and with all quality targets achieved. Served as Lead of Scrum of Scrums for 4 separate Scrum teams (Front-End, Back-End, Install and Tools), identifying, managing and resolving all cross-scrum dependencies.

- Delivered 2 major projects that had fallen behind schedule on time and with full feature sets implemented by utilizing knowledge and volunteering to lead teams after project manager re-organization.
- Reduced build and automated verification from 1x/week to 4x/day, across 5 operating systems by moving team to continuous delivery model.
- Reduced unnecessary emails and slow ramp-up by creating and maintaining over 100 internal wiki pages and tutorials to quickly get new developers on board, as well as to share best practices, tips and techniques among the experienced developers.
- Reduced new developers' onboarding time from 1 week to 1 hour by automatically creating and verifying development environment VMs as part of automated build process.
- Ensured the delivery of high-quality and fully-inspected code by administrating and personally verifying pull requests on 2-code repositories, spanning 1.6M lines of code.

Front-End Development Team Lead

1996 - 2006

IBM Software Solutions

Led 12 developers in design and implementation of new cross-platform, Java-based user interface for IBM Tivoli Business Service Manager (TBSM).

- Reduced manufacturing costs by 50% and verification effort by 25% by consolidating 4 separate DVD-based console installations into 1 downloadable Java Web Start user interface.
- Increased customer satisfaction and decreased support costs by designing and implementing 6 new user interfaces to replace cumbersome and error-prone command line tools.
- Reduced time to upgrade developers' systems from 4 hours to 10 minutes by creating automation tools.
- Enabled automated verification of user interface by developing tools / instrumenting UI code.
- Decreased the time and cost of the i18n verification effort by 25% by designing and implementing tools to automatically identify and report i18n violations during development.
- Increased customer satisfaction and involvement by instituting monthly customer reviews and usability testing and incorporating feedback into designs.
- Ensured coherent and consistent cross-product user experiences by creating and enforcing UI / UX standards across development teams.
- Increased developer productivity by creating 1st internal development Wiki.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Science, Southern Methodist University (SMU), Dallas, TX

CERTIFICATION

Certified Scrum Master (CSM), ScrumAlliance.org